A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Politics - George L. Hinman, Series J.2 FA346
Rockefeller Archive Center
- State Files and Summaries, 1960-1970; 2; 7.6 Cubic Feet
  - Summaries - Political Financial Contributors (Box 90, Folder 613)
- Talent File, 1960-1970; 3; 0.6 Cubic Feet
  Subseries 3 is arranged alphabetically.
  This small subseries contains an alphabetically arranged file of individuals who were recommended to serve on Governor Rockefeller's staff. Some of the individuals sought positions by sending resumes and letters of interest to Hinman, while others were recommended by other members of Governor Rockefeller's staff or friends of Hinman.
  - A (Box 91, Folder 614)
  - B (Box 91, Folder 615)
  - Brinton, William (Box 91, Folder 616)
  - C (Box 91, Folder 617)
  - D (Box 91, Folder 618)
  - E (Box 91, Folder 619)
  - F (Box 91, Folder 620)
  - G (Box 91, Folder 621)
  - H (Box 91, Folder 622)
  - I-K (Box 91, Folder 623)
  - Kimball, Howard (Box 91, Folder 624)
  - L (Box 91, Folder 625)
  - M (Box 91, Folder 626)
  - N-O (Box 91, Folder 627)
  - New York Talent (Box 92, Folder 628)
  - P-Q (Box 92, Folder 629)
  - R (Box 92, Folder 630)
  - S (Box 92, Folder 631)
  - T (Box 92, Folder 632)
  - U-V (Box 92, Folder 633)
  - W (Box 92, Folder 634)
- Memos, 1959-1970; 4; 1 Cubic Feet
  Subseries 4 is arranged chronologically.
  This subseries contains memoranda sent to Governor Rockefeller by Hinman. The memos are entirely political in nature and deal with Governor Rockefeller's political status nationwide. Hinman indicated that many of the memos were "personal and confidential" and were to be viewed only by the Governor. They contain specific mentions of political rivals and strategies that could be implemented in future political campaigns.
  - 1959-1960 (Box 92, Folder 635)
  - January-March 1961 (Box 92, Folder 636)
  - April-June 1961 (Box 92, Folder 637)
  - July-August 1961 (Box 92, Folder 638)
  - September-November 1961 (Box 93, Folder 639)
  - December 1961 (Box 93, Folder 640)
  - January-February 1962 (Box 93, Folder 641)
  - March-June 1962 (Box 93, Folder 642)
  - July-September 1962 (Box 93, Folder 643)
  - October-December 1962 (Box 93, Folder 644)
  - January-June 1963 (Box 93, Folder 645)
  - July-December 1963 (Box 94, Folder 646)
  - January-June 1964 (Box 94, Folder 647)
  - July-December 1964 (Box 94, Folder 648)
  - 1965 (Box 94, Folder 649)
  - January-April 1966 (Box 94, Folder 650)
  - May-December 1966 (Box 94, Folder 651)
  - 1967-1970 (Box 94, Folder 652)
- Correspondence, 1960-1968; 5; 1.5 Cubic Feet
  Subseries 5 is arranged alphabeticallyy subject or organization.
  This subseries contains primarily political materials collected by Hinman in his role as both Republican National Committeeman and chief political advisor to Governor Rockefeller.
  - Albany File - Spring 1966 (Box 95, Folder 653)
    Memoranda, correspondence, clippings, NAR statements and George L. Hinman's handwritten notes on New York City Mayor John Lindsay's tax revenue proposal for the city.
  - Bliss, Ray C., 1965-1966 (Box 95, Folder 654)
    Correspondence and memoranda regarding Bliss, Chairman of the Republican National Committee; clippings and Press Releases regarding the party.
  - Bradshaw, Lester, 1967 (Box 95, Folder 655)
    Memoranda on Wisconsin Primary Law.
  - Burlingham Country Club, 1966 (Box 95, Folder 656)
    Correspondence regarding "non-resident" membership for Hinman in the Burlingame (California) County Club, encloses a brief resume; Burlingame manual.
  - Campaign 1968 (Box 95, Folder 657)
    George L. Hinman handwritten notes from March 1968 meeting held at 812 Fifth Avenue.
  - 1968 Charts and Calendars (Box 95, Folder 658)
    List of Scheduled presidential primaries for 1968; history of presidential primaries.
  - Constitutional Convention, 1965-1967 (Box 95, Folder 659)
    NAR Press releases, memoranda, concerning 1967 New York State Constitutional Convention.
  - Control of Party - George L. Hinman Personal File, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 660)
    Newspaper clippings describing the "split' in the Republican Party.
  - 1968 Convention - Housing, 1967 (Box 95, Folder 661)
    Correspondence and memoranda concerning the designation of James G. Hellmuth as Housing Chairman and the Americana Hotel as the New York Headquarters for the Convention in Miami Bach, Florida.
  - Convention - 1968, 1967 (Box 95, Folder 662)
    Clippings, memoranda, correspondence, and press releases concerning the planning of the 1968 Republican Convention.
  - Convention Job (Pages), 1968 (Box 95, Folder 663)
    Requests for jobs ar convention.
  - Deerfield Campaign, 1965 (Box 95, Folder 664)
    NAR guest at luncheon to support the "Deerfield Capital Gifts Program" held in New York; invitation list.
  - Education, 1964-1966 (Box 95, Folder 665)
    "Excerpts from the New York State Educational Law Relating to State University of New York"; Report "New York State Aid to Students in Public and Private Colleges and Universities."
  - Fifty Million Fund, 1965 (Box 95, Folder 666)
    Correspondence with William H. Hudnut, Jr., National Chairman of the fund to support the Capital Needs of the United Presbyterian Church.
  - Frayn, Mort, 1968 (Box 95, Folder 667)
    Correspondence concerning NAR and the 1968 Presidential Campaign.
  - Governor's Conference 1965 (Box 95, Folder 668)
    Correspondence concerning Governors Conference in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
  - Greenrock File, 1966 (Box 95, Folder 669)
    Clippings, memoranda, and correspondence on William Rodgers book "Rockefeller's Follies".
  - Ab Hermann, 1965-1967 (Box 95, Folder 670)
    "Washington Observer Newsletter" describing Hermann as a "Top Rockefeller Henchman"; memoranda from Ray Bliss on Republican National Committee Plans & Projects.
  - Lindsay Campaign 1965 (Box 95, Folder 671)
    Clippings, "Time" article on NAR-Lindsay relationship; memoranda on the New York City Mayoralty campaign's effect on the 1966 Gubernatorial election.
  - Memo & Letters to George L. Hinman - Miscellaneous, 1962-1964 (Box 95, Folder 672)
  - Platform Analysis Notebook, 1960 (Box 96, Folder 673)
    Report issued on the 1960 Republican Party Platform.
  - Polls, 1967 (Box 96, Folder 674)
    Clippings describing various polls showing electorates' choices for the 1968 Presidential Election.
  - Post Election Moderate Committees, 1964-1965 (Box 96, Folder 675)
    Clippings, memoranda, and correspondence on the Republican Party's future after the 1964 election; Report, "A Proposal to Responsible Republicans," by David B. Goldberg and Douglas L. Bailey.
  - Power Issue, 1967 (Box 96, Folder 676)
    Correspondence regarding the issues of public and private utilities in New York State.
  - "Project #1" - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1963-1967 (Box 96, Folder 677)
    Clippings, correspondence, and memoranda regarding NAR's involvement in the 1968 Presidential Campaign.
  - Publications - Miscellaneous, 1961-1964 (Box 96, Folder 678)
    "America Listen" by Frank L. Kluckhorn, United States State Department (1961) American Heritage Foundation brochure on reforming election laws (1962) Transcript of "Meet the Press" show from August 27, 1961, guest, William Miller Pamphlet, "A Brief Introduction to the John Birch Society" (1962) "Report of the President's Committee on Registration and Voting Participation" (1963) "Republican Positions - 1964" by the Republican Study Group
  - Publications - Mobilization of Republican Enterprise (MORE), 1962 (Box 96, Folder 679)
    Materials on the New York State Republican Party Organization.
  - Publications - Republican Action Committee, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 680)
    Confidential report on a new communications program sponsored by the Republican National Committee.
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "The 1962 Elections", 1963; 3 volumes (Box 96, Folder 681)
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "1962 Republican Party Candidate Help Direct Mail Campaign for Republican Senatorial and Congresional Candidates" (Box 96, Folder 682)
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "Building for Victory '62", 1961; 2 volumes (Box 96, Folder 683)
    Report by Thurston B. Morton.
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "A Fact Book for Republican Campaigners", 1962 (Box 96, Folder 684)
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "A Guide for Republican Women Leaders", 1962 (Box 97, Folder 685)
  - Publications, Republican National Committee, 1961 (Box 97, Folder 686)
    "Kennedy Log" (Daily Chronology, Kennedy Activities and Statements) "500 Kennedy Campaign Pledges, Promises and Programs"
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - Miscellaneous Brochures (Box 97, Folder 687)
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "The Non-White Population of the United States", 1962 (Box 97, Folder 688)
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "Persons of Foreign Stock in the United States", 1962 (Box 97, Folder 689)
  - Publications, Republican National Committee, 2 copies each (Box 97, Folder 690)
    "The GOP Precinct Leader's Manual" "The County GOP Leader's Manual"
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "The Process of Delegate Selection for the Republican National Convention of 1960", 1959 (Box 97, Folder 691)
  - Publications, Republican National Committee - "Social, Economic, and Political Characteristics of the American Population", 1962 (Box 97, Folder 692)
  - Republican Coordinating Committee (Dirksen Committee), 1965-1967 (Box 97, Folder 693)
    Republican National Committee News Releases; Meeting Agenda and Program for Committee; clippings, memoranda, and correspondence on the Committee.
  - Republican Coordinating Committee (Dirksen Committee), 1965-1967 (Box 97, Folder 694)
  - Rockefeller for President Committee - Statement of Organization, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 695)
  - Romney, George, 1967-1968 (Box 98, Folder 696)
    Correspondence and memoranda on NAR's support of Romney campaign.
  - Senator Javits 1965, 1965-1966 (Box 98, Folder 697)
    Correspondence, memoranda, clippings regarding Senator Jacob Javits (R-New York); possible run for Governor in 1962, Presidential run in 1964, statements on New York City Mayoral race.
  - 1966 State Campaign, 1966-1966 (Box 98, Folder 698)
    Memoranda and reports on the outlook for the New York State Campaign.